<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>srcdit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/srcdit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/srcdit/</guid>
      <description>There was a phase when I was editing my .bashrc and .zshrc a lot. Having to edit them and then source them again and again soon became torturous. It would have been so much better if I had a tool to edit and source the files in just one step.&#xA;The best part about being someone who works with and understands software is that I can build a tool to meet this requirement myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asking questions the smart way - summarized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/smart-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/smart-questions/</guid>
      <description>How To Ask Questions The Smart Way is one of my favourite pieces of text related to software development (although the learnings can be extrapolated to other fields too). I adopted it as my Bible back in first semester and have referred it to my friends and juniors in conversations around taking-help a LOT of times ever since.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve also gone back to the document to read it again, but would agree to it being lengthy (it is highly recommend as an investment in yourself though).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First 4 hours of using Neovim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning-nvim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning-nvim/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to give scary Vim a try after I followed a few commands online and got stuck in it 2 years ago. After hacking at it for the past 4 hours, here are some short notes from what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned researching and using neovim.&#xA;What is Vim? In simple words, a text editor which considers the use of mouse to navigate/edit a blasphemy.&#xA;Vim is a modal text editor (it uses different modes in which text can be manipulated).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating Sign Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sign-language-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sign-language-generation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on creating a more accessible space online for the specially abled using AI/ML technologies under my university&amp;rsquo;s Centre of Excellence.&#xA;The What, Why, Who, When and Where About 5% of our country&amp;rsquo;s population suffers from auditory and speech impairment. Most of the educational content available on the internet caters to the &amp;ldquo;mainstream&amp;rdquo; population and lacks accessibility features for those with special needs.&#xA;In order to create a friendlier online space for them, we are working on modules which will essentially translate the content on internet into a more comprehensible form.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I use Linux?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-linux/</guid>
      <description>To start with a small rant on Apple and Microsoft being giant monopolies in the global market for operating systems.&#xA;On one hand, Apple boasts a fluid user experience (and ecosystem lock-in) with its macOS And on the other hand we have Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows which brags its vast support of applications and (pseudo) customizability. Linux, however, speaks for itself. Linux? Linux is a free and open source operating system (technically speaking 🤓☝️, it&amp;rsquo;s a kernel, but for the scope of this post, let&amp;rsquo;s call it an OS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to make a Temperature Converting API using Express.js</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/express-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/express-api/</guid>
      <description>One of the first few tasks of the internship I recently got, was to develop a simple RESTful API which converted a given temperature from Farhenheit to Celsius and vice versa. The choice of technology was left up to me. Having worked with Node and Express.js before, I decided it would be convenient for me to work on the API using these. It would be easier developing an understanding over the API structure and its nuances, without having to worry about learning the syntax of a new language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizing OSDHack&#39;22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/organizing-osdhack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 17:20:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/organizing-osdhack/</guid>
      <description>OSDHack is an annual hackathon, organized by the Open Source Developers Community of JIIT Noida, Sector-62. Previously organized at the intra-college level, this year we decided to scale it up and host a nation-wide open hackathon. We saw registrations of 450+ participants and a whopping total of 100+ teams, which turned out to be way more than we had expected!&#xA;Everything, right from planning till execution was handled by the students of the community and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a piece of cake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documenting my OSDCodeJam’21 experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/codejam-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 02:16:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/codejam-experience/</guid>
      <description>!!! Images broken !!!&#xA;It’s New Year’s Day. We are idling away since it’s our semester break, when around 3 a.m. in the morning, seniors from our college’s Open Source Developers Community (OSDC) made a big announcement. They had come up with a new and unique kind of event for us. OSDC was organizing its first Code Jam, OSDCodeJam’21.&#xA;OSDCodeJam OSDCodeJam is a fun, collaborative (intra-college, but just for this year) competition organized by our seniors from the Open Source Developers Community at Jaypee Institute of Information Technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KWoC&#39;21 Project Mentee Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kwoc-mentee-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 16:52:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kwoc-mentee-experience/</guid>
      <description>Kharagpur Winter of Code (KWoC) is an initiative by IIT Kharagpur’s Open Source Society (KOSS) for students with little to no experience (such as myself) in open source software development.&#xA;It aims to introduce students to the working of one of the most popular version control systems - Git. KWoC helps flatten the learning curve and allows students to prepare further for prestigious open source programs like Google Summer of Code (GSoC), Outreachy, Season of KDE, GNOME Internship program and others.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
